So AI coding extensions are taking over,
but most people are still stuck in 2024
only using cursor or cloth code. So in
this video, I'll explain why these next
generation AI extensions are blowing up
and how you can use them to build
anything. Now my name is David Andre and
I'm the founder of vector.ai and I've
spent well over a,000 hours building
software with AI tools. And you might be
asking, okay, David, why not just use
cursor? Why even bother with all these
new extensions? Well, there are actually
several reasons. The reason number one
is that you can use these AI extensions
anywhere. Maybe you have a VS Code setup
that you really like and you really
don't want to switch to Crystal Windsor.
Well, guess what? Just install an
extension and you can use it right away.
Also, with these extensions, you can use
any provider. Doesn't matter if it's
OpenAI, Enthropic, Gemini, Mistrol,
Deepc, Quen, whatever you want to use,
these modern extensions support it. But
if you only use cloth code, obviously it
only supports enthropic models. And
actually later in the video, I'll show
you how you can use open router to use
any model in existence, no matter if
it's open source or closed source in
these extensions. So make sure to watch
until the end. The third reason is that
these extensions are free and open
source. So instead of paying $200 a
month for cloth code, you can use Kilo
Rue or Klein for free. And on top of
that, they are open source. Now the
beauty of open source is that you can
literally pull up GitHub and look inside
to see how this was made. And if you
have an idea how you can improve it, you
can click the fork button and start
working on your own version today.
Another reason why thousands of people
are switching away from cursor to these
extensions is that they are
customizable. They offer much better
context engineering which is great for
power users. Plus you can actually see
the usage overview. Cursor on the other
hand doesn't have the best reputation
for being transparent about the limits.
Now when you're comparing kilo ru and
client it's important to understand
their relationship why each of them work
and how they came to be. So the simplest
way to understand it is that client got
created as a open-source coding AI
agent. Then someone forked it and
created R code which is a fork of client
and then ruode got forked and that's how
kilo got created. But each of these AI
tools serves a different purpose which
is exactly what I'm going to explain now
so that you know which extension is the
best for you. Starting with client which
is the foundation and it's the most
beginnerfriendly one. The setup is
simple but it's also not that
customizable. Now the way to think of
the other two extensions we're going to
cover RU code and kilo code is as
upgrades to client. However, even if
kilo and ru are more advanced with more
features you still need to know how to
use the fundamentals. And if you learn
how to use client, you'll be able to
easily adapt to any new extension that
comes after it. So, let me show you how
to set up client. And it's actually
very, very easy. All right, so let's
jump into VS Code cursor, whatever code
editor you're using. Open up the
extensions tab right here. Boom. And
type in client. Right there it is. And
if you don't have it already installed,
just click install. Once you install the
extension, you need to open the primary
sidebar. And there it is. There's
client. You might have it on the right.
So, if you prefer on the left like me,
drag it to the left. Obviously, it's the
superior position, but it's fine. You
can still follow along even if you have
it on the right. Anyways, this is what
client looks like. Here we have a
history of recent tasks. Obviously, if
you just install it, it's going to be
empty. At the bottom is the main chat
input field. Above you can decide a lot
more advanced settings such as which
commands to order approve. Anyways,
before we can use client, we have to set
up a model, which means we have to
choose a provider. So, go to the
settings on the left. Click on API
configuration. And here we have to
decide which provider we're going to
use. Now, this decision is very easy
because there's one that allows you to
use all of the models and that is open
router. So, just go to open router.ai
and create an account. This takes like
20 seconds, super easy. Then go to the
top right, click on credits, and make
sure you charge up some money. Just
charge up like $5. Okay, that's going to
be plenty because we can use open source
models which are super efficient, right?
For example, if you click on top right,
you can see a list of all the new models
that just released such as Ernie 4.5 21B
A3B thinking. See, most people don't
even know that Ernie 4.5 exists, which
means they're falling behind. No, I'm
just joking. But basically, here you
have all the models that just released
sorted by uh recency, but uh every
single model you can think of, such as
GLM 4.6, which is one of the best ones
right now, or cloth zone is 4.5 or
deepseek v3.2, every single model is
available on open hour. That's why if
you pay attention for the next 2
minutes, you will know not only how to
use any extension, but also how to use
any AI model that comes out. So go to
the top right, click on keys and click
on create API key. I'm going to name it
subscribe. If you're watching this, make
sure to subscribe. Takes 2 seconds and
it's completely free. All right, so let
me create a key and let's copy this. Now
let me switch back to my empty project
and I have to say do not share your API
keys with anybody. Okay, treat them as
passwords. Then inside of client, let's
switch on API provider. Click on open
router and then simply paste your API
key. Next, we can select which model we
want to use. So maybe you want to use
GBT5. Boom. GBT5. There she is. Enable
thinking. We do want to enable thinking.
Let's do 6,000 tokens. And client
already loads the correct pricing from
open router. So you don't have to worry
about setting up context window or input
output price. This matches exactly GPD5
right here. Boom. You can see everything
is matching. Okay. Let's click on done
and let's send a test message. Who are
you? We're in act mode. By the way, you
can switch to plan mode if you don't
want client to make changes. Okay. And
there is the first response. Now, one
thing you might notice is at the top we
can see advanced context usage, right?
This is something that's completely
missing from cloth code or cursor. These
tools have been like obscured. They have
been not transparent around usage and
people have been complaining that
they're hitting their cloth code limits,
their cursor limits way sooner than they
used to. Right now, before we dive into
the advanced settings of client, let's
first talk about rue. So rue code, the
easiest way to think about it is client
but with powerups. It's best for
intermediate vibe coders who want to
have control over the system prompts,
all the different models, just more
customizability than client offers. For
example, one feature is the slash
commands, right? This is the clear
philosophy of Ruko versus client. You
can set up different slash commands
similar to close code actually where if
you find yourself repeating certain
prompts, just turn it into slash
commands and you save massive amount of
time. By the way, we're adding the same
feature into vectal. So instead of using
notion where you have to repeat same
thing over and over, just use vectali
for your tasks. Speaking of Veectal, we
have made massive improvements. For
example, we have built-in Perplexity
Pro. So, instead of paying $20 a month
for Perplexity Pro, you just get Vectal
and you get all of the AI models with
it, right? We have Sony 4.5, GP4.1, GLM
4.6, all in a single app with a powerful
chat, way more powerful than chat GP
actually. We have SL commands. We have a
productivity agent that can list out
your task, list out my top tasks, and
the chat agent can interact with the UI,
right? So, this is really the ultimate
productivity agent. Instead of using
chat GBD which doesn't have a context on
your tasks, your projects, what you are
currently working on, right? Vexel knows
all of that. You have your taskers here.
If you want to switch to canvan view,
you can do that. Now on the left, you
have the sidebar where you can see all
your projects and with each project you
can set a custom system prompt so that
the chat agent is specialized and
focused just on that project. So if
you're someone who likes to be
hyperproductive and you want to have
access to all of the cuttingedge AI
models in a single spot, go to vectal.ai
and give it a shot. You can get started
completely for free. All right, let's go
back to R code. So one of the biggest
things you have to understand is
indexing. And honestly this might be the
biggest difference between client and
root code is that root code indexes your
entire codebase while client doesn't do
it and they don't do it on purpose. Now
you might be thinking okay David but
what even is a codebase index. Well
think of it as a multi-dimensional
vector database of your codebase. Right?
So your codebase gets converted into
highdimensional vector embeddings and
this enables you to search through it
semantically. So when someone says
authentication, you can get all
different files related to
authentication even if they don't
necessarily mention that word. So here's
a visualization of a three-dimensional
vector database. Now in reality it can
have thousands of different dimensions
but basically if you have let's say
front end you know files on the front
end would be probably semantically far
away from files on the back end or if
they're about the same feature you know
maybe a chat like in vector we have the
chat right maybe a file about the chat
could be semantically closer even if
it's a front end or back end file right
so when you index a codebase you take
all of your files and all of your code
and you put it into something that looks
like this obviously with way more
dimensions And this allows the tools to
search faster, right? So the benefit of
that inside of R code is that you have
faster search. When you type in update
the task list, it will know all of the
files that related to tasks instantly,
nearly instantly. The issue with that is
um maybe some context gets loaded that
you don't want loaded. And this is why
client on purpose decided to not add
indexing. This gives you the choice of
choosing which context is inserted into
the prompt. Plus also in theory it gives
you ability to spend less money because
let's say if some of these tokens that
get sent each time are from the index.
If you don't have any indexing you
obviously don't pay for those extra
tokens, right? So by using client you
should save a bit of money on API costs.
Now actually they wrote an entire
article on this which I'm going to pop
up on screen right here. They took a
controversial stance against indexing
saying that context windows are large
enough. You can just tag the files that
you need. you don't need to do this
advanced indexing. Now, this is
definitely controversial because almost
every other coding tool does index your
codebase. Now, let's look at some of the
main reasons why people like to use R
code over client. First of all, multiple
specialized modes, right? So, if we jump
back in, let me activate R code. And by
the way, the setup is the same. You go
into extensions, you type in R code, you
click on the kangaroo right here. Boom.
Shout out to all the Australians
watching this channel. I don't know how
many of you there are. If you are an
Australian, comment below kangaroo.
Anyways, you install the extension in
the same way, right? And then you
activate it. So, root code. You can see
the logo right here. And it's very
similar to client, the fork of client
obviously, but uh you don't have the
task button like new task and the chat
is a bit cleaner. However, you have
these modes, right? You have architect,
you have code, ask, debug, and
orchestrator. These are basically
pre-built prompts that allow you to do
different parts of your codebase. And
honestly, I'm considering adding
something similar into vectal, such as,
you know, organizing your task,
brainstorming new ideas, planning or
research, different productivity
actions. Let me know guys if you would
like to see that. Basically, different
modes for different types of
productivity or task management actions
that you do. Anyways, this is one of the
biggest differences. You can also do
mode marketplace where you can browse
through different modes created by
either the RU team, you can see at rue
or just random people, right? So if you
want to find something, you can find it
in the marketplace. Same with the MCPS
by the way. Another way to make your
extension more powerful is to connect
different MCPS. You can also use the
vectal MCP here. Anywhere where MCPS are
connected, you can use the ve MCP to
manage your tasks directly from root
code. So maybe you have a project with
your tasks inside of actal and you just
want root codes to execute them. You
would connect the MCP and you would
delegate it to the coding agent. The
next feature people like about root code
is the memory bank support which allows
you to maintain project context and
conic standards across different
sessions. Basically creating memories of
your codebase. It also has enhanced
context understanding and better
handling of large code bases. And I
think this is because of the index
because if your codebase is very very
large, you cannot just tag all the files
in the context window of a single
prompt, right? So that's where the index
comes into play. And we see that with
other tools like augment which really
stresses the indexing. Now there are a
few other reasons why people prefer
using ru. But let's just test it, right?
Why not just to use it ourselves and you
can make up your own mind. And this is
what I would encourage all of you do.
Just install these extensions like the
setup is the same. You can use open
router with all of these, right? Just go
into settings. Boom. We have the
providers on the left. Here I have a GLM
setup through the GLM coding pass. But
then I realized why not just use open
router, right? We have GLM over here as
well. And in a bit I'll explain why this
model is so amazing. So stay tuned
because this model might be the best
open source coding model right now. So
I'll deep dive into this model in a
second explaining what makes it really
good. But what I just realized is that
instead of using this through the Z AI,
you know, Zipu AI, GLM coding plan,
which is a separate subscription and
this and that, you have to set it up
like I did here. OpenI compatible. You
just use it through open router, right?
So the beauty is that if we switch, we
can add a new profile. Boom. Open
router. Create profile provider. Let's
type in open router. Here we will create
a new key. But yeah, there we go. It
also loads the limit. That's nice. And
we can just choose the GLM right here.
Make sure to use 4.6. That's the latest
one. And uh reasoning effort. This is
another benefit here. You can select the
reasoning effort in root code. I'm going
to go with high. You also have some
advanced settings such as to-do list,
editing, match precision. You can see
that root code really is like more
advanced version of client. So depending
who you are, if you are a power user and
you want all the control, maybe root
code is a better option for you. If you
prefer just a simple interface and you
trust the creators of the tool to give
you a nice setup, then client is a great
alternative. Anyways, uh I think we all
of these are good. Just make sure to set
highing effort and then we can click on
save and let's see if we actually hit
GLM 4.6. And the beauty of running it
through open router is that if one of
the providers is down, right? So if we
go to GLM 4.6, we can see that we have a
Jud, Silicon Flow, Deep Infra, GMI
Cloud, Atlas Cloud, Parasale, Novita AI,
and ZAI. This is the official one,
right? Zipi, those are the creators of
GLM4.6, but you can see they have like
pretty low throughput, right? And maybe
their uptime is uh not 100%. So if they
are down, open switches you to a
different one. And if you click on
providers, you can see the different up
times and different throughputs and you
can actually uh use the provider with
the highest throughput to work as fast
as possible. And in the uptime, you can
see the difference, right? Like if you
use a single provider, the uptime is not
that good. But uh if you have the open
router set up, you basically have 100%
uptime always. And in the apps, you can
see how people are using it. So we can
see uh we have R code right here. We
have client right here. And Kilo, which
we're going to get to in a second, is
the second highest user in terms of GLM
4.6 at the moment. But uh let's jump
back and let's actually test it. So who
created you? Let's see if it knows which
AI created this model. Now, as you can
see, R suggests tasks, follow-up tasks
based on what you did. This makes it
much easier for people who are not
creative, right? If you are creative,
you probably know what to do. But a lot
of people are not sure what to do. So
having these like one-click ways, you
know, tell me more about yourself as a
assistant. It's tries to predict your
next action and just make it a oneclick
thing. So as you can see, this is what
it looks like when it answers. It says
like task completed and you can see the
details of the API request as well as
the pricing as well as the thinking. You
can expand that as well in the think
tags. So you can already see the
differences between the user interface
and at the top we also have a different
way of visualizing the context right by
default it's a bit more compact but then
you can expand it and you can see the
details about the context length the
input tokens output tokens API cost and
the size in kilobytes so the creators of
these extensions are opinionated in a
different way and at the bottom you can
see the codebase index right here you
can also disable it if you want so if
you want to use r code but you hate
indexing it's still a possibility now as
I promised let's talk about glm 4.6
because this is one of the best actually
it is the best open source coding model
right now and a lot of people don't even
know that it exists. So before we talk
about Kilo which we're going to get to
let me quickly talk about GM 4.6 because
man this model is amazing. Look at this.
Right. So here we have eight different
benchmarks comparing it to GM 4.5
previous version. Deepseek v3.2. So
that's the latest version of deepseek
cloth 4 set and clot 4.5 set the latest
one from enthropic right chm 4.6
even beats cloth 4.5 set on multiple
different benchmarks. So this isn't just
some random new open source model that
you can ignore. You cannot ignore this
because this is beating the best
enthropic model on several benchmarks,
right? So we have AME25. This is math.
You can see that GM 4.6 is the best at
math. GPQ8 which stands for Google proof
question answer. It's another very
famous benchmark and you can see that
here it almost matches sonet 4.5. Life
codebench v6 it absolutely destroys
sonet 4.5 we have hle I don't know what
this benchmark is but with tool calling
it's amazing right browse comp also
beating enthropic swb bench verified
this is where sonet is much better
terminal bench also the new set defeats
here and ts squared bench is also set is
the best but gm 4.6 six is the best
opensource model. So this model is
actually really really strong and in
some ways on some tasks it will be
better than sonet 4.5 and this is why
you absolutely cannot ignore these
extensions right you might have cloud
code you might have cursor neither of
them have glm 4.6 right now which is
just crazy right so if you're using
codex if you're using cloud code these
are great tools right and at the end
I'll tell you what my thoughts are and
what my current setup looks like because
there is still a time and place to use
codex and cloud code obviously but you
really cannot ignore these extensions
because this is the way to use models
like GM 4.6 that don't really get the
mainstream attention but are crushing
these benchmarks and in many ways they
are much more cost- effective than
enthropic models which are usually the
more expensive types of models. Speaking
of cost, let me break it down for you.
GLM 4.6 currently costs 17th of the
price of cloth sonet 4.5. And as you can
see, it is a comparative model. It's not
like it's significantly worse. It's
literally comparable on some tasks is
even better. And it costs 17th. So set
4.5 costs $3 per million input tokens
and 15 for output. GLM 4.6 index costs
$0.5 per million input tokens and 175
per million output tokens. Now if you
look at this artificial analysis coding
index created by client we can see that
the evolution of opensource models right
so back in 2023 Llama 2 Mr. large. These
models were very behind the closer
models. However, we can see that
recently there has been a closing of the
gap. Thanks to models like Deep Seek R1
or Quen 3, we can see that the cutting
edge of closed source models isn't that
much far ahead compared to the cutting
edge closers models. And it is entirely
possible that 3 months from now, 6
months from now, most of us will be
using mainly open source models such as
GLM 4.6, 6, which already is beating a
lot of these closers models on multiple
different EVAs. Now, honestly, I might
make an entire video on GLM 4.6 and how
good it is compared to other models and
actually building a full software
project with it. So, if you don't want
to miss that, make sure to subscribe.
But now, let's look at Kilo, which I've
hyped up throughout this video. And
there's a good reason because right now,
this is my favorite out of these three.
And you'll see why. Kilo code is if you
want everything from root code plus some
more features while having a simpler
cleaner UI. So basically it takes the
best parts of client and the best parts
of root code and puts it into a new
tool. Now there is a reason why kilo is
often in the top two or top three in
open router usage because uh people are
loving this extension. So as I said it
has the cleanest UI and the most
customizability. For example, the
autocomplete you can select the triggers
such as pause to complete. So when this
is enabled, Kilo will automatically
trigger autocomplete when you pause
typing. And here you can even select the
delay such as 3 seconds. Now actually
while I'm explaining these features, why
not just launch it, right? So again,
extensions. Boom. You type in kilo code.
There we go. Kilo code AI agent. Looks
like this. Install it. You can already
see the UI is cleaner, right? It's less
overwhelming, less cluttered, which is
what I like. Now I'm going to start it
on this project. You can see I don't
have any files. So it's going to be
completely from scratch. And we're going
to use the architect mode. You can see
these modes are similar from rue because
it's built on top of ru code. So let me
paste in my prompt which is basically
YouTube jobs but for AI video creators.
So if you don't know what YouTube jobs
is, it's like a site where you can get
hired as a video editor, right? Or
family creator. This build idea and let
me just launch it real quick is that but
for AI video clips. So you have Soda 2,
you have VO3. AI video is improving
fast, right? And there will be people
who master the creation of AI clips. And
there will also be plenty of YouTubers
and content creators who will pay for
that. Right now, you have to buy
expensive stock footage, but that is no
longer the case. You'll just hire an
expert AI video creator who has mastered
the latest prompt engineering and
context engineering techniques and he
will give you custom on demand clips,
any aspect ratio, any realism or, you
know, any art style you want. This is a
new position that doesn't exist yet that
will emerge over the next 6 months and
they'll probably become a marketplace of
these clips because you have like runway
VO sora all kinds of different tools
that are being created and more coming
from China. There has to be a single
marketplace when you can find these or
sell these or create these right so this
is what we're going to be building right
now or at least the MVP of it. Okay.
Okay, so you can see Kilo has asked me a
question. What's your preferred
deployment environment for the MVP local
deployment only? Simple cloud hosting
like Versell or Railway Render or AS.
Okay, so we're not going to do any of
these uh hyperscalers. That's way too
try hard. We're just going to start with
local right now. And this is really nice
that it's asking these because it lets
you scope out what you're building. Are
you building a quick MVP to validate or
invalidate your idea or are you trying
to build a serious app that needs to be
deployed across like Kubernetes,
containers, whatever. So this is the
architect mode, right? It's really um
tries to understand your vision and it
tries to understand like what you're
trying to aim. If you want to execute,
you have the code mode. If you want to
debug, you have the debug. There's
multiple different modes for a reason,
right? All right. Next question. For the
job marketplace, what's the primary
workflow? I think both workflows or
actually we can probably do this one. So
let's cancel this and let's uh select
this one instead. Perfect. Now I have a
clear understanding of the requirements.
Let me create a comprehensive to-do list
based on your plan. So before it jumps
into work, it creates to-do list. And
you can see at the top, this is the
beauty of Kilo. You see this beautiful
visualization of the context. You can
see like view AI response and you can
click to any of these and you can see
what's taking up context window right
here. Very nice visualization. I think
we're going to see more AI tools
implementing stuff like that. Actually,
I'm considering adding stuff like that
into vectal to visually see your context
build up. It's nice to have the complete
control over the context window. And
here we have the complete to-do list
that kilo created. It's like 13
different things. Kind of comprehensive
to be honest. And now it's creating the
architecture.md.
Very nice. So instead of jumping
straight into code, it creates some
markdown files to plan it ahead. And
this is really the future of AI
programming. I think the vibe coding is
dead. Actually, I tweeted this today and
it caused some controversy. If you don't
follow me on Twitter, David one, go
follow me right now because uh you're
missing out on the spicy takes that I
cannot put on Twitter. Anyways, vibe
coding is dead and we have killed it.
The problem with vi coding is all the
like low-level people that it attracts,
all the people who just like type in a
single prompt and they just want to make
money fast, right? Those type of people
who think building software is just a
joke. It's not a serious endeavor. So,
there's a big difference between vibe
coding and AI programming. And I want to
focus on AI programming going forward
because that's what the serious people
do and that's where the future lies in
building great production ready software
that is fast, reliable, scalable and you
can see that kilo especially in the
architect mode really is optimized for
AI programming. This is far beyond vi
coding. We can see that this coding
agent goes and creates multiple markdown
files before even writing a single line
of code. The amount of planning and
thinking ahead is honestly impressive.
And we can see that this agent is
running like it is putting in the work,
right? I'm not doing anything. My hands
are lifted and it is using GLM 4.6 to go
through this to-do list to design the
data model schema mock the data services
implement user authentication system
mocked before even writing any code so
that it can plan it ahead. It can see
like okay based on what the user has
told me, based on the complexity of the
system, what is the best text stack?
What is the best codebase structure?
What is the best modular system? What is
the best file length? What is the best
uh naming scheme for the functions and
files? All of these things are like less
about coding, more about architecture,
right? I mean, we're in the architect
mode. So, this is like software
architecture, software design. This is
what VIP corders have zero clue about.
Now, honestly, the architect mode might
have been an overkill for this MVP. So,
I'm going to start a new task while this
is running. And it's going to be in the
code mode. Same prompt. I was just going
to say now get to work and make this
happen. The fewer lines of code the
better. This is one one of my favorite
pros by the way. The fewer lines of code
the better. Really great when doing AI
programming. Now because we already have
the architecture and system flows files
created from the architect earlier. The
coding agent now can execute way faster.
And I already gave it a pretty detailed
prompt. So it should be it should be
doing just fine. Now while this is
running, let me explain another reasons
why people like kilo over ru or client.
For example, we have the quick task
which is similar to command k inside of
cursor. So actually I can show you that
just right here. So maybe I don't like
the structure of this job class. I can
do command k. I can say um simplify this
class, right? And this is basically
targeting a single isolated portion of
the code. And see it removed some
sections. I'm going to undo that because
that's messing with the plan that Kilo
proposed. Command I is the same feature
inside of Kilo. And then also the manual
autocomplete. This is very interesting.
If you need a quick fix completion or a
refactor, Kilo can use the surrounding
context to offer immediate improvements,
right? And this is a autocomplete. So
you don't have to specify what you need.
It's basically like a command K, but it
tries to guess your intent. And this
really shows that the team behind Kilo
is experimenting fast with new features.
And I would say they're the fastest
moving of these three AI coding
extensions. And we've also seen this
with the speed of adding GLM 4.6. Right?
So this is a as we've said this is a
very powerful model that is the best
open source coding model right now. I
would say the best coding model is
definitely GPD5 codex with high
reasoning effort. But more more on codex
in a bit. But you can see that GLM 4.6
was added by Kilo on September 30th,
while Klein took three more days. Still
was fast, but Kilo is really on top of
it. These guys are grinding now. Because
of how logged in the team behind Kilo
is, I reached out to them asking if they
want to partner on future videos, and
they responded within like 2 hours. So,
I was like, "Listen guys, I'm making a
video on AI code extensions. Do you want
to sponsor this one?" And they agreed.
So, I'm not changing any of the
conclusions I said, but I do want to
tell you about the team plan of Kilo. So
if you are someone in charge of a team
of developers, you really need to look
into the Kilo team plan because this is
one of the best offerings I've seen.
First of all, you get smart controls. So
you can see that your team isn't using
models that are leaking your data. A lot
of these model providers actually train
on your data. And if you have a
proprietary codebase, like a lot of
serious companies do, you need to make
sure that nobody on your team uses these
models. With the Kilo team plan, this is
super easy. There's also zero login.
Kilo is open source, so you can use
their API or you can use your own keys.
You can even use local models. It's
completely up to you. And honestly, if
you are smart, the Kilo team plan will
actually save you money because you can
see who on your team is overperformer,
overachiever, who deserves the next
promotion, and who's kind of falling
behind, you know, kind of not using the
tools, not really adopting to the
cutting edge of AI. Plus, it lets you
ensure that everyone on your team is
using the latest and greatest AI model
out there. So if you want to build a
serious software company or if you
already lead a team of developers, the
kilo plan for teams is really something
you should look at. It's going to be
linked below the video and the amount of
things you get for single subscription
is kind of crazy. So again, go check it
out and thank you to Kilo for sponsoring
this segment of the video. So anyways,
let's jump back to see where the coding
agent is. So it's creating the back end.
Okay, we can see that the this is a
proper codebase structure. It's actually
taking way longer than I expected. And
as you can see, Kilo has these nice
checkpoints that you can return at any
moment in case something went wrong.
Right now, obviously, if you work on a
serious project, you should learn how to
use Git. A lot of you guys are scared of
Git for no reason. Now, Git, not to be
confused with GitHub, is a version
control system, right? So, it allows you
to do basically these checkpoints, but
in a much more scalable and professional
way. And again, if you're just building
a quick MVP, maybe you don't need to set
up a git repo. But if you are working on
something for more than a day, okay,
more than a day, you absolutely do need
to set up a git repo. And that's where
GitHub comes into place because GitHub
is a way to just store different Git
repositories, right? But Git is just a
version control system. So if you want
to visit a version before you did a
risky change, right? An older version of
your code, that's where Git comes into
place. So these checkpoints, don't let
these fool you, okay? A lot of vibe
coders would rely on these checkpoints.
That's a huge mistake, guys. Just learn
how to use git. It is super simple.
Actually, in the new society, we have a
module just on this, right? So this is
inside of the classroom right here in
the section code with AI. Here we have
GitHub fundamentals which explains both
Git and GitHub. And this is just one of
many different advanced tutorials you
can find in the new society. So, if you
are serious about coding with AI and you
want to go to the next level, join the
new society. It's going to be linked
below the video. Now, back to Kilo.
Let's see if it's still going. And it is
still going. Wow, this is very
impressive. This coding agent can run
for 10, 15, 20 minutes at a time. And
you can see on the right, we have a
proper codebase structure. So, this is
not just VIP coding a single file. This
is building and architecting a codebase
so that you can turn this into a serious
project, right? And maybe I overkill
this to be honest or u a quick demo, but
yeah, this coding agent can go for a
while. And at the top you have control.
So right now we've spent $0.5. So this
is if you used like Sonet 4.5 or
especially Opus. If you used Opus 4.1,
we would already be like 10, 20, $30.
But with GLM 4.6, so like you can you
can probably start seeing the beauty of
these extensions. Right now, as I
promised, let's talk about clo and codex
because when should you use these two,
right? They still have a time and place
and I still use these every single day.
Now, these extensions are starting to
take up more and more of my time, right?
So, maybe like two months ago, I wasn't
using client ru or kilo, but now I'm
using this more and more. Why? Well,
there's many reasons, right? Uh,
personally, I don't really care about
cost, but that's because of, you know,
I'm building my software company. I'm
building vector. So cost is part of the
cost of building a software startup,
right? But also because I'm interested
in the best performance. And now that we
see in the last two or three months
especially, we see open source models
catch up to the cutting edge of the best
coding performance. I'm starting to use
the extensions more and more, but also
because of the fact that they can run
for so long without like you having to
constantly step in and because of the
fact that they give you a complete
overview of the tokens, right? And
nobody likes to get scammed. Even if you
have a high budget, you like to, you
know, get your money's worth. And the
fact that we still haven't spent a
single dollar, like less than $1. And
look how many files have been created.
Look how much output. Like this is
crazy. So yeah, when should you use
close calling Codex? To answer the
question, right now Codex, especially
with the new GPT5 CEX model, which by
the way also is available inside of open
router. So you could use this model. You
could use this inside of kilo or rue or
client if you wanted to. This model is
currently the best, right? And with
codex, you have different reasons. It's
not just a coding agent inside of your
IDE. Codex also gives you the
cloud-based agent, right? Which you can
dispatch like 10 different tasks to and
which can work on multiple things at
once asynchronously. But Codex also
released the GitHub PR review. So any
single pull request you make, COEX can
look through it and spot any potential
issues. So that's another thing, right?
Codex isn't just one product. It's like
four different products right now.
Speaking of cloth code, it's mostly used
for the terminal, right? Close code, you
can launch it, use it in the terminal,
and it's like a autonomous agent which
really pioneered the AI coding agents
earlier this year. It's kind of crazy
that all of this happened in 2025. Now,
as I said, I still use both of these.
The main main reason for cloud code is
that the UI in the terminal is just
polished. It's the best UI in the
terminal out of all of these. Codex CLI
is getting better, though. They just
shipped, I think, the 045 0.45.0 update,
which is very nice. It improved the UI
of the CLI, but it's still not as
polished as cloth code, right? And I do
have to say I am using cloth code less.
Some of that has been delegated to
extensions like kilo. As I said, kilo
out of these three is my favorite, but
some of that most of that actually went
into codex. So, codex is the most
powerful right now, bar none. And that
is mainly because of this model GPT5
codex. This model on medium and high
reasoning effort is a beast. It's the
most reliable model. It just puts in the
work. It spends like if you are doing a
risky change, it can spend 10 15 minutes
just planning and preparing before it
writes any code. Now the beauty of this
model, what OpenAI really cooked is that
if it's a simple change, it will not
spend 10 minutes, right? it might reason
for 30 seconds and then get to work. But
if it's a risky change, either like a
big refactor or like a massive new
feature, it will put in the work,
especially on the high reasoning effort.
And this model is amazing. So yeah,
Codex, the beauty of that is it's
integrated, right? So you have the Codex
uh web agent. Let me show you that.
Boom. Right here. You can give it
multiple tasks and then inside of the
codeex in uh your extension right here,
you can browse for these tasks whether
cloud-based or local based and you can
just continue working on them like that
which is huge. Here you can literally if
you're like listening to your users
right maybe here you guys can comment
different ways to improve vectal which
by the way we have the discord server so
if you are a vectal user you can just
talk to me or the developers any day and
you can suggest features and that's why
this is the fastest improving software
in the world and that's why we're going
to build this into better chat agent
than JGBD especially for productivity
and task management that's where we're
focusing right and a big part of that is
the discord server when anybody can
suggest features and I can just dispatch
a codex task like that, right? So, if
you are a vector user and you spot a
suggestion or you spot a bug, me or the
other devs, we can just instantly deploy
a Codex cloud-based agent on it, right?
And then it can be running multiple
tasks in parallel and then when I
actually have the time to clean those
up, I can just jump in, boom, load up my
Codex extension, load up the cloud-based
tasks, and just work on them one by one.
So, this is the beauty of the Codex.
It's a whole ecosystem and OpenAI is
really cooking and they're coming for
Enthropics launch. They're not only
coming for Enthropic launch, they're
coming for Crystal's launch as well. So
yeah, OpenAI is on fire and that's why
if I had to choose a single coding tool,
it would have to be Codex. But these
extensions are not to be overestimated.
They're shipping fast. The teams behind
them, they're aggressive, right? They're
putting in the work. They're shipping
features, new models all the time. And
the issue with these two they will
always stick to their models only.
Right? So right now cloth code if it
allowed other models would be amazing.
Now obviously there's ways to use the
cloth code UI through other models but
by default cloth code only counts with
enthropic models. Same with codex. Codex
only counts with openi models which
currently that's not an issue because
they do have the best coding model in
the world. But when they when they don't
you know could be next week could be
next month. Hey Gemini 3 is around the
corner. Gemini 3 might get released any
day now. If it is really that amazing,
you cannot use it inside of Codex,
right? And then we will see the rise of
Kilo. We will see the rise of RU. We
will see the rise of client. People will
be wanting to use Gemini 3. Now,
obviously Gemini has the Gemini CLI, but
it's probably the worst CLI tool out of
them all currently. Maybe they improve
it. They will probably improve it
knowing the team behind Google and Deep
Mind. These guys are cracked. But you
can see that the code, the landscape is
changing, right? The landscape is
changing literally week to week. So
while cloth code was the king two months
ago, it is not the king anymore.
Currently the king is codex, right? But
uh hey maybe next month it will be kilo
with Gemini 3. Or maybe GLM will release
a new model GLM 4.7, right? Or maybe
Deepseek finally drops Deepseek R2 or
Deepseek V4. Who knows guys? Who knows?
The key is to stay adaptable, right?
That is the secret. People ask me,
David, what is the secret? The secret is
to stay adaptable. The AI space is
changing all the time. If you are one of
these people who just uses a single tool
and like refuses to experiment, refuses
to learn, you will fall behind
inevitably. You have to be willing to
adapt and you have to be willing to try
one new tool a week, right? This is the
things that I'm teaching people in the
new society. No matter what is your
setup, you should master your setup.
What every single week, you should try
at least one new tool. And if you want
to be on the cutting edge, join the new
site because this is where I can share
the thoughts. This is where you have the
people who are on the cutting edge of AI
coding and who really are sharing all of
the latest things when it comes to
startups, when it comes to AI agents,
when it comes to AI coding. If you are
serious about programming with AI and
you want to take your skill set to the
next level, join new society. We have
tons of advanced content such as how to
build an AI startup, how to build a real
AI business, or how to build your first
AI agent. A lot of you just want to get
into it. You want to improve your skill
set to prepare yourself for the future.
New Society is the place for that. Plus,
every single week we host a call where
you can join, ask any questions, get
hands-on help, and this is the easiest
way for you to speak with me directly
and, you know, pitch me startup ideas,
ask me any questions, whatever you want
to do. New society is the place to do
it. So again, the New Society is going
to be linked below. Yeah, hopefully you
guys find this video valuable and I have
a feeling that this is not going to be
the last video on these coding
extensions. With that being said, thank
you for watching and have a wonderful,
productive week. See you.